(Sincro: wyxchari)
Retain full pressure.
保持最大压力
Full pressures being maintained on master control.
Reserves are standing by.
主控已经保持在最大压力上．备用系统待命中
Let me see. Let me see.
让我看看, 让我看看
Doctor, what could be happening to Jamie now?
博士, Jamie 现在会怎样？
I hate to think. It won't be anything very pleasant.
我不敢去想．不会有什么愉快的事情
Polly, go and see what the first dial
on the control desk registers.
Polly, 过去看看控制台上第一个读数
Right.
好
Hurry up.
快点
Full pressure.
满压
Full pressure. And the other one? Come on.
满压．另外一个呢？快
Zero.
零
Zero. Now I think there's only one thing for it.
Plus must be made minus and minus must be made plus.
零．现在我觉得只有一种可能．加得变成减, 减得变成加
What's the matter?
什么情况？
The question is which is plus and which is minus?
问题是哪个是加, 哪个是减？
Ooh.
噢
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
Oh, just checking.
哦, 只是检查一下
Well, I don't need your help, thank you.
好吧, 我不需要你的帮助, 谢谢你
As you please. But, uh, I think you're going to
run into trouble.
你高兴就好．不过, 啊, 我觉得你要陷入麻烦了
Why? What's the matter?
为什么？什么情况？
Well, according to my calculations,
the pressure gauges are wrong.
哦, 根据我的计算, 压力表读数是错的
Don't be ridiculous.
别瞎说了
Ridiculous? Well, that's as may be.
But, after all, three times three is nine,
瞎说？好, 也有这个可能．但, 毕竟, 3 乘 3 得 9
and if you divide by half of its own cubic capacity
to the formula, Pi over four squared,
然后如果你按这个公式用它容积的一半去除, ４π的平方
I think you'll have to agree with me.
我想你就会认同我了
Don't touch that.
别碰那个
Why not?
为什么不能？
That's the... That controls the inflow system.
那是...那控制着流入系统
Oh. So these are the inflow pipes, are they?
That's all I wanted to know.
哦．那就是这里有流入的管道, 是吧？我就想知道这个
But what are you doing?
不过你要做什么？
Inflow. Inflow. Outflow. Inflow. High pressure.
Low pressure and O-U-T spells out.
流入, 流入, 流出, 流入, 高压, 低压, 然后是 O-U-T
Doctor, what are you doing?
博士, 你在做什么？
It's alright, Polly.
Confusion is best left to the experts.
没事的, Polly．混乱最好留给专家来处理
But... Stop it! You've no idea what you're doing.
但是...停下！你不知道你在做什么
Oh, yes I have. I can stand an operation on its head
quicker than anyone. There!
哦, 我知道．我可以从头进行操作比谁都快．那里！
I think you'll find I've revolutionised
the entire gas flow of the Colony.
我想你会发现我已经革新了这个殖民地的整个瓦斯流向
You must be mad. You'll be locked up.
你肯定疯了, 你会被关起来的
Polly, see what those dials register now.
Polly, 现在去看看那些仪表读数
Right. Doctor? Something's happened to this one.
好的．博士？这一个出了点问题
What does it read?
它什么读数？
It's reads zero.
读数为零
And the other one?
另外一个呢？
Full pressure.
满压
Good. Splendid. That means there'll be a fine old gale
of fresh air blowing along the old shaft any time now.
好, 非常好．这意味着很快将有一大股新鲜空气刮过旧竖井
Ah! Ah! Let go! No! Let... Not yet, you're not.
啊！啊！放开！不！放...还不要, 你不是
You can do nothing. You'll only delay matters.
It's a simple matter for me to reconnect the gas.
你什么也做不了, 只会延误事情fixme．我要重新连接这些瓦斯是件很简单的事情
Yes, I'm sure it is. But I'm sure you'd like a little help.
是的, 我确信是这样．但我也确信你需要一点点帮助
Now stop that. You've enough to answer for already.
现在停下那个．你已经有足够多的问题要回答了
Guard! Guard!
警卫！警卫！
It's all right, Polly. I've got his keys. Lock the door.
没事的, Polly．我拿了他的钥匙．锁上门
Send the guard, immediately!
派警卫过来, 立刻！
They're bound to get in sooner or later.
他们迟早肯定会来的
Yes. Well, the later the better.
是, 不过, 越迟越好
The only thing we can do for Jamie now
is to give him time. Lock the door.
现在我们唯一能为 Jamie 做的, 就是给他时间．锁上门
This is Control. Why has the outflow of gas stopped?
这里是管理员．为什么流出的瓦斯停下来了？
Gas must be pumped into the old shaft without interruption.
Begin pumping immediately.
瓦斯必须不间断地泵入到旧竖井里面．立即开始抽取
I need help immediately. The strangers obey nothing.
They are turning taps in the wrong direction.
我急需帮助．异乡人什么都不服从．他们把阀门都转了向
Guards have been detailed to assist you.
已经向警卫详述了情况, 他们过来帮你
Open up in there!
里面把门打开！
Keys! My keys! Where are my keys?
钥匙！我的钥匙！我的钥匙在哪儿？
Oh, dear. Your keys. Try, uh, in your pocket.
噢, 亲爱的, 你的钥匙．啊, 试试你的口袋
Or on the gantry. Or over there.
或者在台子上, 或者在那边
Look, I know you've got them.
听着, 我知道你拿走了
Doctor, the door.
博士, 门
Open up in there or we'll smash it in.
里面把门打开, 否则我们就砸了
It's going to give way.
快要扛不住了
Come on, Polly. Let's get out of here.
快点, Polly, 我们离开这里
No, not that way - it goes to the pits. Quick. Try that one.
不, 不能走那边 - 那通向矿坑．快点, 试试那边
It's locked.
被锁住了
Then use the keys. Quick, Doctor. Quick!
那用钥匙．快, 博士, 快！
Over there. Quick! Stop them before they do any damage.
在那边, 快！阻止他们, 以免他们搞破坏
Get them!
抓住他们！
Push, Polly! Push!
推, Polly! 推！
I can't!
推不动！
You've got to. Come on. Together. I've nearly got it locked.
你必须得．快点, 一起．我快把它锁上了
There we are.
这下好了
Where are we?
我们在哪儿？
Well, it looks rather like a cupboard with a lot of pipes.
哦, 看起来是一个碗柜, 上面多了好多管道
Where do you suppose they lead?
你觉得它们通向哪里？
They must lead somewhere. Let's have a look.
它们肯定通向某个地方．我们去看看
Doctor, I think these are the pipes
that carry the poisonous gas.
博士, 我觉得这些管道里面跑的是那些有毒瓦斯
Yes, very likely.
是的, 很有可能
Well, don't you think we'd better stay here?
那, 你不觉得我们最好待在这里吗？
Stay here? I'm not spending the rest of my life
with a lot of old pipes.
待在这里？我可以不打算跟一大堆管子共度余生
But Doctor...
但是博士...
Now, come along Polly. I'm sure there's no need to be afraid.
现在, 过来 Polly．我确定这里没什么可害怕的．
Well... well, I think there's no need to be afraid.
Oh, come on. Let's find out.
这个...我想没有必要害怕．噢, 快点, 我们去搞明白
There, that ought to do it. Let's hope we're not too late.
那里, 那应该可以了．让我们祈祷我们没有来得太晚
What do you know?
你知道什么？
We all know Control is right, and we must obey!
我们都知道管理员是对的, 而且我们必须服从
Let them know. Let them know.
让他们知道, 让他们知道
Let them know they're happy!
让他们知道他们很幸福！
Greet the morning with a shout.
向着清晨喊一声你好
Everyone up. The sun is out.
所有人都起来, 太阳出来了
Rah, rah, rah!
Rah, rah, rah! Cheer for the Colony.
We're the gang that works the hardest,
and we must obey. Obey Control. Ring the bell.
Rah, rah, rah!
Work well.
好好工作
Ring the bell!
Oh, that's much better.
But, we'll do it again, and this time with more feeling.
噢, 这次好多了．但, 我们要再来一次, 这次多带点感情
Ah! And don't forget our job is to inspire the others
啊！而且不要忘了我们的任务是要鼓舞其他人 -
- our brave workers who are doing such a dangerous job.
All right?
那些干着如此危险工作的勇敢工人．好吗？
All right!
好！
What do you know?
你们知道什么
We all know Control is right, and we must obey!
我们都知道管理员还是对的, 而且我们必须服从
Let them know. Let them know.
让他们知道, 让他们知道
Let them know they're happy!
让他们知道他们很幸福！
Greet the morning with a shout.
向着清晨喊一声你好
Everyone up. The sun is out.
所有人都起来, 太阳出来了
Rah, rah, rah!
Oh, that's very good!
That's beginning to sound like something.
噢, 这次非常好, 听着开始像点样子了
It still needs a bit more clarity,
and I think that the girls could...
还需要更清晰一点点, 而且我觉得姑娘们可以...
Say! how did you get there?
说！你怎么到这里来的
Oh, w... well, uh... I just, um... as a matter of fact...
噢, 我...这个, 啊...我只是, 唔...事实上
Oh, I see. You're one of the dancers.
哦, 我明白了．你是跳舞队中的一员
One of the dancers? Oh, I'm afraid, uh... Aye. Aye,
y... y... yes. I'm one of the dancers.
跳舞队的一员？哦, 恐怕, 啊...是, 是, 是的, 我是其中一员
And you got your dance ready?
那你准备好你的舞蹈了吗？
My dance? Ah... Well, uh... Yes. Yes, it's ready.
我的舞蹈？啊...这, 啊...是的, 是的, 准备好了
Well, go ahead. I'll see it now.
那, 开始吧．我现在要看看
You'll see it now?
你现在就要看？
And don't forget you have to be very good
to get into the Happy Colony finals.
而且不要忘了, 你必须表现非常好才能进入快乐殖民地的决赛
We want something gay and cheerful.
我们想要欢乐明快的
Gay and cheerful?
欢乐明快的？
Have you any music?
你有音乐吗？
Ah, no. I don't need it.
啊, 不, 我不需要
Go ahead. We'll pick up the rhythm and clap to it.
All right?
开始吧．我们会跟着节奏打拍子．好吗？
All right!
好！
Well, come on. Get on with it. We haven't got all day.
好, 快点．开始跳啊, 我们没有一整天
Oh, aye.
噢, 是
That's very good. What do you call it?
这非常好, 你管它叫什么舞？
The Highland Fling.
高地猛冲
Why do you call it the Highland Fling?
你为什么管它叫高地猛冲？
Because we finish the dance
by flinging ourselves out the door.
因为我们结束舞蹈时都是冲出门去？
Oh, that's very good! Come on now. Rah, rah, rah!
哦, 这太棒了！现在都来, 剌, 剌, 剌！
Rah, rah, rah!
Cheers for the Colony. Rah, rah, rah!
为殖民地欢呼, Rah, rah, rah!
Where did this boy come from?
这个男孩儿哪里来的？
Oh, he's one of the dancers.
哦, 他是跳舞队的一员
Nonsense. He's the escaped stranger. You there
- identify him. Is this the boy you reported?
胡说．他是个逃跑的异乡人．你 - 指认一下, 这是你报告的那个男孩吗？
Well... Well... Yes.
这个...这个...是的
Ben, you gave me away.
Ben, 你出卖我
Tie him up. Go to the Pilot. Tell him the stranger's found.
把他绑起来．到领航员那里去, 告诉他异乡人已经找到了
Tell him it won't be long before we get our hands on
his friends as well.
告诉他不用太久我们也会抓到他的朋友们了
Jamie, I'm...
Jamie, 我...
No permission for the guards to go on forbidden ground.
Repeat, no permission.
警卫没有进入禁地的权限．重复, 没有权限
They are not to cover the exit to the old shaft.
他们不得去把守旧竖井的出口
This is in use at this moment by Control.
No one is to go near the old shaft.
当前它正在被管理员使用, 任何人不可进入或者靠近旧竖井
Shh. I hear voices. Very faint.
嘘, 我听见有声音．很轻
I don't hear anything.
我什么也没听见
Stay here a minute, Polly.
在这里待一分钟, Polly
No. Don't leave me.
不, 别扔下我
The search for the other strangers must be carried on.
对其他异乡人的搜索工作必须开展
The Controller. The voice behind the screen.
管理员．声音在屏幕后面
All guards are detailed to hunt for the Doctor
and the girl. They must be taken dead or alive.
所有警卫都派去搜寻博士和那个女孩儿．无论死活, 必须找到
Look! He must be there.
看！他肯定在那里
This is Control. The day shift is to begin work
in the emergency gas shaft.
这里是管理员．白班即将开始在紧急瓦斯竖井中工作
All pressures are to be maintained.
The Colony cannot live without gas!
必须保持瓦斯压力．没有瓦斯殖民地无法存活！
So that's where all the gas goes.
看来所有瓦斯都去了那里
Yes. Just as I thought. These creatures would die without it.
是的, 如我说料．没有它们这些生物就会死
But how long have they been there? I mean,
they weren't always in control, were they?
但它们在那里多久了？我是说, 它们不是一直都在fixme
I couldn't tell you when they were here
in the first place, Polly.
我无法告诉你它们一开始是什么时候在这里的, Polly
They're like germs in the human body.
它们就像人类身体内的细菌一样
They've got into the body of this colony.
They're living as parasites.
它们进入了这个殖民地的身体, 像寄生虫一样生活
You make it sound like a disease.
你说得好像一种疾病似的
Polly, that's what I think they are.
Polly, 我觉得它们就是那样
They're in the control room.
It must be like getting into the brain, mustn't it?
它们在控制室里面, 这肯定就像是钻进大脑一样, 是不是
Yes. Very likely.
是, 非常可能
Shh. They might hear you.
嘘, 它们可能会听到你
Now then. One system must provide them with the gas they need,
and the other one must be an outflow.
现在，一个系统肯定是给它们提供所需的瓦斯的，另一个肯定是排出口
Doctor, we've got to bring the Pilot here.
Then we can show him these creatures really do exist.
博士，我们得带领航员到这里来。然后展示给他看这些生物真的存在
Yes, Polly, I think it might work.
是的，Polly。我觉得这样可行
Look at me when I talk to you.
我跟你说话的时候，要看着我
Ola, a word with you.
Where exactly did you catch him?
Ola, 问你一句，你具体是在哪里抓住他的？
In here. In the hall, Pilot.
在这里，大厅里，领航员
I see. So, in fact, he gave himself up?
我明白了，这么说，事实上，他是自首的？
He should never have been allowed to escape.
本来就不应该允许他逃跑
Are you criticising Control?
你是在批评管理员吗？
I'm criticising the running of the pits.
我是在批评矿坑的运作
But that is my job, Ola.
但那是我的工作，Ola
I know that. But were it not for my guards,
this stranger would still be a danger to all of us.
我知道。但如果不是我的警卫，这个异乡人仍然是我们所有人的危险
I am going to report to Control that
there is no discipline in the pits.
我要向管理员报告，矿坑毫无纪律
That's not the only report that Control will get!
那可不是管理员会收到的唯一一份报告！
Ever since these strangers arrived
your authority in this colony has gone to pieces.
自从这些异乡人的到来，你在这个殖民地的权威已经崩溃了
They come and go as they please,
and even now two of them are still missing.
他们想来就来，想走就走，就是到现在他们还有两个人不知去向
Good morning. Good morning. Good morning.
Well, everyone is up bright and early.
早上好，早上好，早上好。好，每个人都早早起床了
And the last two strangers are not missing after all.
Oh, come now.
最后两个异乡人也没有失踪。哦，现在来吧
You can't have bad temper and differences of opinion
in this happy type colony.
在这个幸福的殖民地，你不可能会有坏脾气和不同意见
Say you're sorry, Ola. Say you're sorry, Pilot.
说你很抱歉，Ola。说你很抱歉，领航员
Doctor, what did ye come here for?
You've walked into a trap.
博士，你来这里做什么？你走进了陷阱里了
Good morning, Jamie.
Nice to see you so well cared for.
早上好，Jamie. 很高兴看到你受到如此多的照顾
Yes, but Doctor...
是，但是博士...
Oh, it's all right. I've just come in
to have a word with my old friend, the Pilot.
哦，没事的。我只是进来跟我们的老朋友，领航员，说两句话
Good morning, Ben. I hope you're feeling more your old self?
早上好，Ben，我期望你觉得更像是以前的你了
Yes, Doctor. I am.
是的，博士，我是
Why did not your guards arrest these strangers?
为什么你的警卫不把这些异乡人逮捕起来？
I don't know. Guards, arrest them!
我不知道。警卫们，逮捕他们！
That is no longer necessary.
不在有这个必要了
Of course not. You can't arrest us
now we've given ourselves up.
当然没有。现在我们都投降了，你不能逮捕我们
That's against the rules.
这违反规则
Now. You wish to see me?
现在，你们想要见我？
Yes. I do. Urgently. Come with me.
是的，我想。很紧急，跟我来
This is Control. Everyone is to return to work immediately.
这里是管理员。所有人立即返回工作岗位
This order includes all executives. It includes the Pilot.
这项命令也包含管理层，包含领航员
Everyone back to work immediately.
所有人返回工作岗位，立即
Well, I shall have to go.
但，我得走
No, wait. You must listen to
what the Doctor's got to tell you.
不，等等。你必须听听博士要告诉你的事情
They're only saying that because they know what we've seen.
他们那么说仅仅因为他们知道我们看见了什么
At once!
马上
Pilot.
领航员
At once! That is an order!
马上！这是命令！
Don't take any notice of them. That's not your Controller.
Those are your enemies.
别管他们。那不是你们的管理员，那是你们的敌人
There must be no discussion with the strangers!
不允许同异乡人进行讨论
Why not?
为什么不？
Aye. What are you afraid of?
是，你在害怕什么？
Arrest the strangers! That is an order!
All the strangers!
逮捕异乡人！这是命令！所有异乡人！
That doesn't sound like a man in control.
那听起来不像是一个大局在握的人
What did you wish to tell me?
你想要告诉我什么？
Pilot. You heard Control.
Guards, take them all away.
领航员，你听到管理员的话了。警卫，把他们带走
I am still the Pilot here.
You will take your orders from me.
我仍然是这里的领航员。你得听从我的命令
Get back to your quarters.
回到你们的房间去
Contact Control immediately. Report the Pilot!
立即联系管理员，举报领航员！
That was a very brave thing to do.
那可真是非常勇敢的行为
Or very foolish. What is it you wanted to tell me?
或许是非常愚蠢。你想要告诉我的是什么？
Come with me.
跟我来
Pilot!
领航员！
You will all remain here.
你们全部都得留在这里
He disobeyed Control.
The Pilot will be arrested.
他不服从管理员。领航员得被逮捕
No.
不
Anything may happen now, Jamie.
We've got to be ready to run for it.
现在什么都可能发生，Jamie。我们得准备好逃跑
We can't leave the Doctor.
我们不能撇下博士
He'll be back in a minute,
and Ben seems to be all right now.
他一会儿就会回来，而且 Ben 现在似乎也没事了
More like the old Ben, I must admit.
But you still canna...
更像以前的 Ben 了，我必须承认。但是你还是不能...
Where is he?
他在哪儿？
But, Doctor. This is forbidden territory.
但是，博士，这里是禁地
Yes, and you'll soon see why.
是的，而且你很快就能看到为什么
Stop! Stop! You're breaking the law!
停下！停下！你是在违反法律！
Bad laws were made to be broken. Follow me.
坏的法律制定出来就是要违反的。跟我来
But...
但是...
What's happened to the Pilot, Ola?
The strangers have changed him!
领航员发生什么事了，Ola？那些异乡人已经改变了他！
The Pilot is a traitor.
领航员是个叛徒
The Pilot has no more authority.
Ola is in command!
领航员不再具有权力了。Ola 掌权指挥！
I really don't know why I trust you, Doctor.
我真的不知道为什么我相信你，博士
Oh, perhaps I've got an honest face.
哦，也许是我有一张诚实的脸
The Pilot is to be arrested!
This is a happy colony! All must obey!
领航员将被逮捕！这是一个幸福的殖民地！所有人都要服从！
Did you hear that?
你听到那个了吗？
Don't give up now. It's just up here.
不要现在放弃。就在上面这里
All guards to report to the pit head.
They are to take orders from Ola. It is understood.
所有警卫带矿坑 fix 报到，从 Ola 那里接收命令。fix
There you are. That's what's taken over this colony.
这就是啦，那就是接管了这个殖民地的东西
You haven't been in touch with Control, but with these.
跟你们接触的不是什么管理员，而是这些
They've used this colony for their own ends,
destroying you to live themselves.
他们利用这个殖民地达到他们自己的目的，毁灭你们来让他们生存
Why...they're horrible. No, Doctor.
It is they who must be destroyed.
为什么...它们太吓人了。不，博士。它们才是必须被消灭的东西
We must kill them.
我们必须杀死它们
They're here!
他们在这里
Let's go.
我们走
The Pilot and the stranger!
In forbidden territory! They must be destroyed!
领航员和异乡人！在禁地里！必须消灭他们！
So, what are they, Doctor?
I mean, some monstrous form of bacteria?
那，它们是什么，博士？我说，某种可怕的细菌吗？
Insects? Or what?
昆虫？或者别的？
I don't know. But you must fight them.
我不知道，但你必须同他们斗争
How?
怎样才能？
Take full command!
全面夺权！
You mean defy Control?
你的意思是反抗管理员？
Well, you see what Control really is.
是，你都看见了管理员真正是什么
Yes. You're right, Doctor, they must be destroyed.
是，你是对的，博士。必须消灭它们
We've been waiting for you.
我们在等你呢
Ola, the Colony is in the hands of
grotesque insects!
Ola, 殖民地在这些怪诞的虫子手中！
So you've been seeing things?
所以你也能看见东西啰？
They're in there. The Macra!
它们在这里，那些 Macra!
Ha, ha, ha. You know
what happens to people that say that?
哈哈哈，你知道说这个的人都怎么样了吗？
But I...
但是我...
Now we can deal with you all together.
现在我们可以一并处理你们了
Did the Pilot has see them?
领航员看见它们了吗？
Yes. I saw the Macra.
是的，我看见 Macra 了
It is forbidden to say that.
Don't let him say that he has seen Macra!
怎么说是被禁止的。别让他说他见过 Macra!
I saw you! You are the Macra!
我见过你！你就是 Macra!
Silence! Silence the three strangers!
That is an order!
安静！三个异乡人都闭嘴！这是命令！
What shall we do with them, Control?
我们要拿他们怎么办？
Return them to the pipe room.
The three strangers and the Pilot.
把他们送到管道室，三个异乡人和领航员
They are to be locked in,
and you will not let them out.
他们要被锁起来，你不能让他们出来
Come on, get in.
快点，进去
Ola.
Doctor!
博士！
Come on. You heard Control.
快点，你听到管理员的话了
Don't worry Polly, I'll look after ye.
别担心 Polly，我会照顾你的
No!
不！
Take your hands off her.
把你的手从她那里拿开
Get in!
进去！
You have done well, Ola.
你做得很好，Ola
What instructions, Control?
什么指示，管理员？
Clear the building. Guards and workers
are to return to the hall for music.
清空大楼。警卫和工人们都返回大厅听音乐
I obey, Control.
我服从，管理员
It will take precisely four minutes, and then
it will be safe for everyone to return to work.
这将需要整整4分钟，然后每个人就可以安全地回去工作了
- Four minutes.
- Why four minutes?
- 四分钟  - 为什么是四分钟？
Aye, what can they do in four minutes, Doctor?
是，四分钟里面它们能做什么，博士？
I don't know. We must be ready for anything.
我不知道，我们必须准备应对一切
It's a gas! It's coming in here.
是瓦斯！进这里来了
Pilot, do you know where it's coming from?
领航员，你知道它是从哪里来的吗？
Why, no. I've never been here before.
为什么，不。我以前从没来过这里
There must be a hidden inlet.
肯定有一个隐秘的入口
You will not be able to fight it.
You cannot stop it.
你们没法对抗它，你们阻止不了它
Doctor, I'm getting dizzy.
博士，我头晕了
Polly, hold that in front of your mouth.
Polly，把这个捂在你口鼻上
It's coming from over here, Doctor!
它是从这里来的，博士！
You're right, Jamie!
你是对的，Jamie!
It's coming from here as well!
这里也可以出来！
You are unable to stop it.
你们没法阻止它的
Polly?
It will not last long. Only for four minutes.
By that time, you...
不会太长时间，只有四分钟。到那个时候，你们...
Come on! Let us out!
快点！让我们出去！
...will be completely helpless,
not quite dead, helpless.
...将会完全无力，还没有完全死，而是无力
Hello in there.
里面的人呐
Who is it?
是谁？
Ben.
Ben? Is that you? Are you all right?
Ben? 是你吗？你没事吧？
Can you open the door from your side?
你能从你那边打开门吗？
No.
不能
But it's locked. There isn't a key.
它是锁上的，没有钥匙
Ben, listen. We've got very little time.
It's all up to you.
Ben, 听着，我们只有很少的时间了。全靠你了
Go ahead Doctor. Tell me what to do.
继续博士，告诉我该怎么做
Go to the control desk, and you'll see two switches,
到控制桌去，你可以看到两个开关
one marked outflow and one marked inflow.
一个标记着流出，一个标记着流入
Hang on.
坚持住
The other stranger has recovered.
He is dangerous now!
另外那个异乡人已经恢复了。他现在很危险！
He will no longer obey Control.
The fourth stranger is trying to help his friends.
他不再服从管理员了．第四个异乡人试图帮助他的朋友。
He is no longer one of us. He must be stopped at once!
他不再是我们的一员了。必须马上阻止他！
I've got them, Doc. Two switches. What next?
我找到他们了，博士，两个开关。然后怎样？
Good. You see a lever in front of them?
好，你看见它们前面有个拉杆吧？
Yeah.
嘢
It is forbidden to touch that instrument!
You must not obey the Doctor!
触碰那个设备是禁止的！你不能听从博士的！
You will kill us all!
He intends to create an explosion!
你会杀死我们全部的！他打算引发一场爆炸！
Come away from those instruments!
You will destroy the Colony!
离开那些仪器！你会毁了殖民地的
Oh, shut up. Okay, Doctor. Fire away.
噢, 闭嘴！好了, 博士, 点火吧
Guards! Stop the stranger!
警卫！阻止那个异乡人！
Switch on both inflow and outflow.
同时打开流入和流出
No! Stop! The pressure will be unbearable!
Oh, the human beings as well...
不！停下！压力将会变得无法忍受！噢, 这些人类也会...
Switch them on, Ben. Then stand by to throw the lever.
把它们打开, Ben．然后准备推拉杆
You are to give no such order!
你无权给这样的命令！
Inflow on. Outflow on. Okay, Doc. Ready with the lever.
流入打开, 流出打开．好了, 博士．准备拉杆
Quickly, Doctor!
快点, 博士！
Throw the lever away from you.
将拉杆推离你
No! No! Don't let him.
不！不！不能允许他
No!
不！
My first duty is to thank the strangers,
for they have saved our Colony.
我的第一个职责是要感谢这些异乡人, 感谢他们救了我们的殖民地
A dance festival will be held every year in their memory,
and the winners will be awarded the Strangers' Trophy.
舞蹈节会每年举行, 以纪念他们．比赛获胜比赛的人会赢得异乡人战利品
Where's the Doctor?
博士哪里去了？
Why, he's right over there.
咦, 他刚才还在这里
Well, I've got a tip-off he'll wanna hear.
哦, 我有一个秘报他肯定想听
Hey, Doctor? Doctor?
嘿, 博士？博士？
Relax. Relax. More haste, more waste. Pleasure is beautiful.
放松, 放松．越着急就越浪费．快乐是美丽的
Relax? You wait till you hear
what they're going to do with you.
放松？你等着听听他们要把你怎么样
Oh, well. Ha, ha, ha.
噢, 噢？哈哈哈
Yeah, I just heard it on the grapevine.
是的, 我刚才在葡萄架fixme上面已经听到了
They're going to draft us as members of the Colony,
and make you the next Pilot.
他们要把我们列为殖民地的成员, 让你担任下一任领航员
They can't do that to me. Let's get out of here.
他们不能这么对我．我们离开这里吧
Yes, but how?
是, 但怎么弄？
Take a leaf out of Jamie's book.
Give them the old dance routine.
从 Jamie 的书里扯一页, fixme